<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speedrun on Nicolas Mohnblatt</title>
    <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/blog/speedrun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speedrun on Nicolas Mohnblatt</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024-2026, Nicolas Mohnblatt.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nmohnblatt.me/blog/speedrun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paper Speedrun: Protostar</title>
      <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/speedrun-protostar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nmohnblatt.me/speedrun-protostar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is cross-posted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://geometry.xyz/notebook/paper-speedrun-protostar&#34;&gt;Geometry Notebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Note that the ProtoStar paper has received many updates and some of the cross-term optimisations described in this speedrunm may no longer be up to date.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;: ProtoStar: Generic Efficient Accumulation/Folding for Special Sound Protocols&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Authors&lt;/strong&gt;: Benedikt Bünz and Binyi Chen&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/620&#34;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/620&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: ProtoStar presents three results: 1) a generic toolchain to obtain efficient folding schemes from special sound protocols, 2) a simple special sound protocol for Plonkup where the prover does not depend on the size of the lookup table and 3) a non-uniform IVC scheme based on the former results. Their folding scheme follows the same pattern described in Nova/Sangria (relaxation of the equations) but introduces an optimisation to avoid committing to cross-terms: instead of checking $l$ equations of degree $d$, ProtoStar batches them into a single equation of degree $(d+2)$ and $2\sqrt{l}$ equations of degree 2. The cross-terms from the degree-2 equations can be committed to using the Pedersen vector commitment (as in Nova) and those arising from the single high degree check can be committed to using the identity function (the &amp;ldquo;commitments&amp;rdquo; are still short enough and binding!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Speedrun: zk-creds</title>
      <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/speedrun-zkcreds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nmohnblatt.me/speedrun-zkcreds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is cross-posted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://geometry.xyz/notebook/paper-speedrun-zkcreds&#34;&gt;Geometry Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; zk-creds: Flexible Anonymous Credentials from zkSNARKs and Existing Identity Infrastructure&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Michael Rosenberg, Jacob White, Christina Garman and Ian Miers&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;: paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/878&#34;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/878&lt;/a&gt; , code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rozbb/zkcreds-rs&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rozbb/zkcreds-rs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: zk-creds is an anonymous credentials system. A credential is a Pedersen commitment to attributes. The credential is shown to be valid in ZK and issued by adding it to a public list. A credential can be &amp;ldquo;shown&amp;rdquo; by proving in ZK that the committed values match some access criteria and that the credential is included in the issuance list. Privacy is maintained by blinding proofs. The paper also introduces Merkle forests and a protocol to blind and link Groth16 proofs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
