<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identity-Based Encryption on Nicolas Mohnblatt</title>
    <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/blog/identity-based-encryption/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Identity-Based Encryption on Nicolas Mohnblatt</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024-2026, Nicolas Mohnblatt.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nmohnblatt.me/blog/identity-based-encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-preserving Contact Discovery for Bluesky</title>
      <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/arke-for-bluesky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nmohnblatt.me/arke-for-bluesky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, we released Arke &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/1218&#34;&gt;[MSGJ24]&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol for &lt;strong&gt;privacy-preserving contact discovery&lt;/strong&gt;. We also shared an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asonnino/arke&#34;&gt;experimental prototype&lt;/a&gt; of the system which we used to run geo-distributed benchmarks for our paper. Since then, the paper has been peer-reviewed and published in ACM-CCS&#39;24.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal is to allow users of an existing social graph (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, 𝕏) to find each other and construct a new graph (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, Bluesky) without revealing either of the social graphs nor publicly linking the existing and new accounts. I encourage you to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/blog/contact-discovery/&#34;&gt;this article by Moxie Marlinspike&lt;/a&gt; for more context on why contact discovery is desirable and hard to do privately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emulating Witness Encryption with Threshold Cryptography and ZKPs</title>
      <link>https://nmohnblatt.me/witness-encryption-from-ibe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nmohnblatt.me/witness-encryption-from-ibe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short document outlines how to emulate witness encryption using threshold cryptography - and more specifically, threshold identity-based encryption (IBE). The ideas presented here are heavily inspired by the &lt;code&gt;tlock&lt;/code&gt; construction from &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/189&#34;&gt;[GMR23]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I have not done a thorough review of the existing literature, if you are aware of existing constructions that work in the same way please let me know!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Witness Encryption.&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;em&gt;extractable witness encryption&lt;/em&gt; paradigm is the following: given an instance of some hard problem, one can encrypt a message using the instance such that it may only be decrypted by someone who &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; the problem&amp;rsquo;s solution (the witness).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
